Elham Kareem Dino

Address: Sinjar - Iraq
Tel: 07503345725

Email: <u>elhamkareem919@gmil.com</u>

Date of birth: 12th April 1994

Nationality: Iraq Gender: female

A civil engineering diploma degree holder, motivated, respectful and trustworthy humanitarian activist individual, with rich experience within, humanitarian field, evaluation monitoring and community liaison & coordination, I have gained tremendous experience from my job with different Orgs. such International Org., NGOs, CBOs and construction Co., as well as I had gained much enough experience during my job in office and in field how to communicate and deal with people, works in team and make achievements. I am very easy approachable person always demonstrates to fulfil my duties, and use my skills to priorities tasks and administer my time and my duties.

WORK HISTORY

NRC Org. May 2021 – Dec. 2021

Job title: UDOC Technical Assistant

- Checking with the NGOs in Sinjar to know the last update service map.
- Referring vulnerable cases to the service providers.
- Record and document the referrals.
- Follow up on the referred cases to ensure having good quality service.
- communication with the cases is aware of the expected services to be provided.
- Collecting feedback from the cases and the NGOs about the referrals.
- Organizing files on the computer and in hard copies, making sure I have back up of all files.
- Organizing the hard copies of the document with having a smooth archiving system.
- Inform the incentive staff about their tasks.
- Follow up during the assessments.
- Submitting the payment of the incentive staff on time.
- Support in Develop, maintain databases and IM tools. Conduct regular quality control of data with
- coordination with the IM officer.
- Assess and monitor data and information systems to improve the efficiency and accuracy of UDOC Data.
- Conduct and monitor surveys and assessments as needed under the supervision of the IM Officer and UDOC PC
- Ensure that all data collection, storage, analyses and dissemination is in line with NRC's data protection principles

SOSD Org. January 2021–May 2021

Job title: Case Worker - Sinjar, Iraq

• Provide individual or group Psychosocial support where survivors can receive compassionate, and confidential assistance focusing on children, women undergoing fear and trauma.

- Form support group for survivors and care givers to enhance their recovery as they respond to traumatic.
- Provide group activities for survivors and other women that focus on building support networks, community reintegration, building confidence and skills, and promoting economic empowerment
- Conduct psychosocial support activities targeting School students, liaise with School administration by strengthening youths' voices and concerns are listened to.
- Establishing a network of peer helpers, including the training and technical supervision of the peer helpers. As well as attending supervision and training courses

Care Organization April 2020–Dec. 2020

Job title: Field Assistant - Sinjar, Iraq

- Coordinating tasks according to priorities and plans
- Assist the CM in establishing and maintaining regular contacts with community groups and committees.
- Performing all distribution carried out by IRD to the community
- Assigns the roles and duties of acting field officer when he is on leave.
- Producing schedules and monitor of works.
- Allocating general and daily responsibilities
- Coordinate tasks according to priorities and plans
- Resolve problems when they arise
- Report on progress to field officer.

NRC Org. Dec. 2019 – April 2020

Job title: Meal Assistant - Sinjar, Iraq

- Assist with the implementation of the support function portfolio according to plan of action.
- Prepare and develop status reports as required by management.
- Ensure proper filing of documents.
- Promote and share ideas for improvement of the support function.
- provide regular progress reports to Area Manager (AM), Project Managers (PMs) and M&E Coordinator.
- coordinate process to establish and/or standardize program level M&E system.
- Support in developing data collection methodology and tools, and in actual data collection, as needed.
- Support and contribute to the development of a data management system through documentation, implementation and coordination of standardizes information flow of M&E activities and reporting.
- Conduct field monitoring and verification of implemented projects as needed.
- Support in developing data collection methodology and tools, and in actual data collection, as needed.
- support in data management and development of clear information flow between program and M&E staff.
- Conduct qualitative and quantitative field monitoring and verification of project implementation.
- Ensure that monitoring data are reported on a timely manner to relevant program and managerial staff.
- Contribute to area level M&E concept note development and participate in log frame design during project proposal and planning process.
- capacity building and training of program staff on M&E technical and conceptual areas, as needed.
- Any other task relevant to the position as requested by line manager and Country Office (CO) M&E Coordinator.

Medair Humanitarian Org., Part time (Friday and Saturday)

Dec. 2019 - March 2020

Job title: Women Awareness volunteer – Sinjar, Iraq

Within these 4 months, I joined their awareness team, performed awareness activities, consisted of conducted community visits, meeting people, deliver female related awareness subjects, identified various types of case, referred to appropriate service providers in the area, made groups to receive female hygiene and health awareness sessions.

Nahdat Sinjar Co. Feb. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Job title: Site Engineer – Sinjar, Iraq

- Rehabilitation the streets, sidewalks and central landscape island in Sinjar.
- Putting the work schedule plan.
- Making verbal and writing reports to the management at the end of every working day.
- Always made sure the construction items, tools and materials are available on site.
- Documenting and recording project events in writing and following up the work

IOM Org. Dec. 2016 – Dec. 2017

Job title: Hygiene Prometer - Zakho Qadia IDPs Camp, Iraq

- The main purpose of the role is to deliver hygiene & health awareness to the women in the camp.
- Worked in a team of 10 hygiene promoters, prepared and delivered group sessions.
- Managed to deliver 7 group sessions (30 participants) mainly focusing on female hygiene.
- Participated in the distribution of female hygiene materials among women.
- Conducted awareness sessions in the community center & also within the community.

EDUCATION & TRAININGS

2018 Technical Institute

Mosul, Iraq

Diploma degree in Civil engineering

NRC Organization- 2019

Collaborative Dispute Resolution training

NRC Organization - 2019

GBV Basic Concept & Referral pathway training

NRC Organization- 2021

HEIST Achievement Certificate

International Rescue Committee (IRC) - 2019

Introduction in the CP & Wellbeing training

Handi Cap Organization - 2019

Inclusion & protection training

GIZ Organization-2017

Community Social and Legal Support Center training

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Excellent computer, Microsoft Office skills/ work manageable skills.
- Experienced in working with national and international organizations.
- Excellent team work member, flexible, can work in groups and individually.
- Work with team to compile appropriate documentation for assessments before and after work is completed on each home, including photographs, bills of quantities, assessments, etc. .
- interviewing with and registering beneficiaries' information by Kobo collect and ODK collect.
- Excellent humanitarian activist and service delivery management skills, highly organized person.
- Very good supervising and team leading skills can manage people from different backgrounds.
- Excellent public speaking experience and skills, can communicated with people effectively.
- Good organizing, administration and time management skills.
- Communication and building relationships, diplomatic person/ excellent skills.
- Customer service skills and good negotiations experience.

LANGUAGES

| Languages | Understand ing | Reading | Writing | Speaking | |
|---------------------|----------------|-----------|---------|----------|--|
| Kurdish (Native) | Fluency | Fluency | Fluency | Fluency | |
| Arabic | Fluency | Fluency | Fluency | Fluency | |
| English | Very Good | Very Good | Good | Good | |

Reference are Available Upon Request.